--==本字幕由 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩字幕 请关注 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric
如果你发烧 咳嗽 或者嗓子痛的话 请呆在家里
If you have a fever and cough or sore throat... stay home.
我觉得这东西有95%的可能是人工制造的 来自一个实验室
I'd say 95% chance this is manufactured. Came out of a laboratory.
这个病毒的来源...
The source of the virus was traced back...
是在旧金山的人工基因实验室里进行的药物测试
to drug testing done at Gen-Sys Laboratories in San Francisco.
首个病例是实验室里的一个技术员...
The lab technician now known as Patient Zero...
意外地被逆转录病毒ALZ-113号感染...
was accidentally exposed to retrovirus ALZ-113....
这是一种正在猩猩身上进行试验 用于治疗老年痴呆的药物
an Alzheimer's trial drug that was being tested on chimpanzees.
被感染的猩猩展现了反复无常并极具攻击性的行为...
The infected chimps showed signs of erratic and aggressive behavior...
并最后逃出了这个机构
that led to their escape from the facility.
著名的金门大桥事件...
The now-famous incident on the Golden Gate Bridge...
猩猩们和警方僵持了六个小时...
a six-hour standoff with police...
最后消失在了红木林里
ended with the apes disappearing into Muir Woods.
急诊室里挤满了大批的病人...
Emergency rooms are being overwhelmed with patients showing signs...
他们感染了我们现在所说的"猿流感"
of what's being dubbed "The Simian Flu."
疾病控制局估计...
The CDC is projecting a fatality toll...
在接下来的6到8个月里 死亡人数会有...
ranging from 5 million to as many as 150 million...
五百万到一亿五千万
in the next 6 to 8 months.
所有出现感染了传染病迹象的人都将在这里...
Anyone showing signs of a contagious illness will receive special treatment here...
机场中专门建造的隔离中心接受特殊治疗
the airport's purpose-built quarantine center.
这里的很多新来的孩子们都和他们的父母失去了联系
Many of the new arrivals are children who have lost contact with their parents.
强制的隔离激发了动乱
The mandatory quarantines have sparked civil unrest.
- 一个个家庭分崩离析 - 这个疾病目前不太可能得到控制
- Families are being ripped apart. - Containment is not very likely.
和你的家人们做好准备 熟悉疏散路线
Prepare your families. Know your evacuation route.
目前的存活率是五百分之一
The survival rate is now approximately 1 in 500.
今晚在市中心爆发了暴力事件
Violence erupted in the city center tonight.
这是这几天内发生的第三次类似事件
The third incident in as many days.
在28个国家中 包括美国和加拿大 都颁布了战争法
Martial law has been declared in 28 nations including the U.S. and Canada.
核反应堆已经过热了 我们没法阻止核熔毁
The reactor is overheating. We can't stop a meltdown.
这是社会秩序的彻底崩塌
Just a total collapse of anything resembling civilian order.
由于这次极端的猿流感危机...
Due to the extremity of the Simian Flu crisis...
所有的政府功能都完全停摆
all regular government functions have been suspended indefinitely.
那些没有被病毒杀死的...
Those who aren't killed by the virus...
也很可能在暴力冲突中死亡
will probably die in the fighting.
所以 也许就这样了
So, maybe this is it.
这就是末日
This is how it ends.
很快...
Pretty soon...
所有人都会死
there won't be anyone left.
猩球崛起: 黎明之战
凯撒...
Caesar...
他们在接近了
They are close.
科巴!
Koba!
父亲 现在怎么做?
Now, father?
孩子 你待着...
Son, stay...
谢谢你 科巴
Thank you, Koba.
孩子 三思而后行
Think before you act, son.
蓝眼 别伤心...
Don't feel bad, Blue Eyes...
伤疤会让你更强壮
Scars make you strong.
来见见你的新弟弟
Come meet your new brother.
又生了一个儿子
Another son.
这让我想到我们已经走了那么远了 毛里斯
Makes me think how far we've come, Maurice.
好像是很久以前
Seems long ago.
你还想着他们吗?
Still think about them?
人类?
Humans?
有时候会想
Sometimes.
我不像你那么了解他们
Didn't know them like you did.
我只看到了他们恶毒的那一面
Only saw their bad side.
善良还是恶毒... 现在也都不重要了
Good, bad... doesn't matter now.
人类互相毁灭
Humans destroyed each other.
猩猩之间也会打斗
Apes fight too.
但我们是一个家庭
But we are family.
我不知道他们是不是真的都走了
Wonder if they're really all gone.
已经过去十年了...
Ten winters now...
近两年... 都没看到他们
Last two... no sign of them.
他们一定已经走了吧
They must be gone.
蓝眼 那头熊伤不到我的 我动作很快!
That bear wouldn't get me Blue Eyes. I'm quick!
灰烬 闭嘴!
Shut up, Ash!
天啊
Oh, God.
没事
It's okay.
没事的 没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
不许动!
Freeze!
不许动! 救命啊!
Stay! Help!
救命啊! 不要!
Help! No!
嘿!
Hey!
这里来!
Over here!
我打中他了! 我打中他了
I shot him! I shot him.
他们向灰烬开枪了! 他们打中了我儿子!
They shot Ash! Shot my son!
火箭 等等...
Rocket, wait...
我们无意冒犯!
We don't mean any harm!
哥们 他们是猩猩 你觉得他们听得懂你讲话吗?
They're apes, man. You think they understand what you're saying?
你觉得他们看起来是普通猩猩吗?
Do they look like just apes to you?
- 爸 - 马尔科姆 你在干什么?
- Dad. - Malcolm, what are you doing?
- 爸? - 马尔科姆
- Dad? - Malcolm.
没事的
It's okay.
把你们的枪放下
Put your guns down.
- 不会吧 - 照做就行
- You can't be serious. - Do it.
给我滚!
Go!
- 我靠 - 我靠
- Holy shit. - Holy shit.
好的 我们马上走
Okay. Okay, we're going.
滚!
Go!
慢慢来 我们走
Slowly. Go, go, go!
- 我的包! - 赶紧走
- My bag! - Go!
科巴!
Koba!
跟着他们!
Follow!
你找到了吗?
Did you find it?
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
怎么了? 有什么问题吗?
What? What's wrong?
水坝差不多保存完好
The dam is pretty much intact.
大概一个礼拜之内 它就可以开始为我们发电了
It could probably start generating power for us within a week.
但是我们有个麻烦 上车说
But there is a problem. Get in.
我打中他了 我很害怕 我不知道怎么办
I shot him. I was scared. I didn't know what to do.
天啊 他们有多少?
Jesus Christ. How many were there?
很多 差不多80只
A lot. Like, 80.
- 至少这数 - 好吧...
- At least. - Okay...
你没在仔细听 他们说话了!
you're not hearing what he's saying. They spoke!
不可能
That is not possible.
相信我 德雷福斯 他们真的说话了 真是难以置信
I'm telling you, Dreyfus, they did and it was incredible.
难以置信? 他们是会说话的大猩猩!
Incredible? They're talking apes!
- 他们还有很大的矛! - 拜托!
- With big-ass spears! - Please!
我不知道你到底看到或者听到了什么...
I don't know exactly what you think you saw or heard...
但你必须冷静下来 行吗?
but you have to calm down, okay?
还有那个病毒呢? 艾莉 我们有没有可能被感染?
What about the virus, Ellie? Any chance of contagion?
我们都是在基因上对这个病毒免疫的 否则我们早就死了
We're all genetically immune or we would've been dead a long time ago.
- 你也不确定吧 - 她在疾控局工作 她确定
- You don't know that for sure. - She worked with the CDC. She knows.
- 我们该怎么办? - 不知道
- What are we gonna do? - I don't know.
- 我们需要电力 - 他本可以杀了我们的 但他没有
- We need that power. - He could've killed us, but he didn't.
也许他放我们一条活路 然后跟踪我们
Maybe he kept us alive, so they could follow us.
他们可以找到我们的住所 然后把我们一网打尽
They find out where we are, and they kill us all!
- 什么意思 你说"他"? - 我们一直想告诉你
- What do you mean, "he"? - That's what we're trying to tell you.
这事前所未见 他们有一个领导者...
It was unlike anything you've ever seen before, and the leader...
- 他太惊人了 - 真的?
- He was remarkable. - Really?
- 你们是这么想的? - 这是我们亲眼所见
- Is that what you thought? - It's what we saw.
我们所有人都目睹了
Yeah, it's what we all saw.
回到居住区 什么都不要说 懂吗?
Not a word of this back at the colony, you understand me?
在我们想出对策之前什么都不要说
Not a word until we can figure out what to do.
- 你一定是在逗我 - 不 我是认真的
- You gotta be kidding. - No, I'm not kidding.
我不想让大家恐慌
I don't want to create a panic.
兄弟 你怎么样? 你还好吗?
How are you doing, pal? Are you okay?
- 我把我的包弄丢了 - 我知道
- I dropped my bag. - I know.
- 你的画图本在里面吗? - 它不见了
- Was your sketchbook in there? - It's gone.
卡佛跟我说 我们之前遇到的事情不能告诉任何人
Carver just told me we're not gonna tell anybody what happened up there.
现在暂时不行
Not yet. No.
我们必须现在进攻他们!
Must attack them now!
否则他们就要来攻击我们了!
Before they attack us!
我们不知道他们到底有多少人
We don't know how many there are.
也不知道他们有多少枪
How many guns they have?
我们也不知道他们为什么在这里
Or why they came up here?
火箭 他们开枪打了你儿子!
They shot your son, Rocket!
你不想大战一场吗?
Don't you want to fight?
我会追随凯撒
I follow Caesar.
科巴说的对!
Koba's right!
他们差点就把你杀了 灰烬!
They almost killed you, Ash!
不行!
No!
如果我们开战...
If we go to war...
我们有可能失去一切...
We could lose all we've built...
我们的家园
Home.
我们的家庭
Family.
还有我们的未来
Future.
我会在明天早上之前做决定
I will decide by morning.
凯撒
Caesar.
我在他们的实验室里被囚禁了好几年...
For years I was a prisoner in their lab...
他们用刀切我...
They cut me...
折磨我
Tortured me.
是你让我获得自由
You freed me.
你要我做什么我都会照做
I would do anything you ask.
但是我们必须展示自己的力量!
But we must show strength!
我们会的 科巴
We will, Koba.
借过 借过
Coming through. Coming through.
这可远远不止八十个了!
That's a hell of a lot more than eighty!
马尔科姆!
Malcolm!
我们猩猩...
Apes...
不想开战...
do not want war...
但如果别无选择...
but will fight...
我们会死战到底
if we must.
那里是我们猩猩的家园
Ape home.
这里是你们人类的家园
Human home.
不要再来了
Do not come back.
各位!
Everyone!
你们要冷静下来!
Everyone, you have to calm down!
各位
Everybody.
各位!
Everybody!
求你们了! 我们是免疫的!
Please! We're all immune!
我们都是免疫的 否则我们就不会在这了!
We're all immune, or we wouldn't still be here!
他们怎么找到我们的?
How did they find us?
是我们找到了他们
We found them.
- 你知道他们在那! - 他们回来怎么办?
- You knew they were out there! - What if they come back?
对啊!
Yeah!
如果他们回来... 如果他们回来了...
If they come back... If they come back...
他们会后悔的!
they'll be sorry they ever did!
现在我们这个城市也许不像以前一样有那么多人 但是我们有火力优势
Now, this city may not have the manpower it once did but it has the firepower.
我们有联邦应急管理局
Those stockpiles left behind by FEMA,
和国家守卫队留下来的装备
the National Guard, we have it all.
你们听我说...
Look...
我知道你们为什么害怕
I know why you're scared.
相信我 我也害怕
I'm scared, too, believe me.
但是我知道你们都信任我
But I recognize the trust you've all placed in me.
我们一起经历了那么多
We've been through hell together.
但是你们都知道我们面对的是什么
But you all know what we're up against.
我们马上就没有燃料了
We're almost out of fuel.
这样我们就没有电力...
Which means no more power...
那我们就倒退到以前了
which means we could slip back to the way things were.
那个水坝是我们的解决方案
That dam up there was the answer.
我们只是没想到他们也在那里
We just had no idea they were up there, too.
- 那我们现在怎么办? - 对啊!
- So, what do we do now? - Yeah!
我们另寻出路...
We find another way...
因为电力... 并不仅仅是可以用来开电灯
because that power... is not just about keeping the lights on.
这给我们与整个世界连接的工具
It's about giving us the tools to reconnect to the rest of the world.
让我们找到其他人...
To find out who else is out there...
这样我们才能开始重建...
so that we can start to rebuild...
并夺回...
and reclaim...
我们失去的世界
the world we lost.
这演说真棒
That was a great speech.
没有替代的电源了
There is no alternative power source.
那个大坝是我们唯一的选择
That dam is the only option.
那我们和他们死战到底
Well, then, we fight them.
我们还有两个礼拜就没有燃料了 最多三个礼拜
We're two weeks away from running out of fuel. Maybe three, tops.
- 我知道 - 一旦如此...
- I know. - And once that happens...
我就没法拿着扩音器...
I won't be able to go out there with a bullhorn...
让大家冷静下来了
and calm everybody down.
我们需要电力来使用无线电发射器
We need that power to get the radio transmitter working.
这是我们和外界取得联系的唯一方式了
It's our only chance of reaching the outside world.
我们必须找到其他的幸存者
We have to find other survivors.
是啊 人类已经所剩无几了
Yeah. There's not that many of us left.
- 我们没法再接受更多的伤亡了 - 我们建立了这里的一切...
- We can't afford any more casualties. - We founded this place...
- 我和你... - 我知道
- you and I... - I know.
因为电力可以带领我们回到曾经有过的生活
On the idea that power would lead us back to the life we once had.
如果我们不能团结一致 我们也许就不能存活了
If we can't stick together, maybe we can't survive.
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
如果我再失去现在仅有的这些 那...
The idea of losing what little I have is...
我要回到那里去
I want to go back up there.
听我说 给我三天时间
Listen to me. Give me three days.
让我和他谈一谈 如果没用 我们再按照你说的来
Let me talk to him. If it doesn't work, then we do it your way.
万一造成了反效果呢? 万一他变得很暴力怎么办?
And what if it backfires? What if he gets violent?
你怎么知道他能理解你?
I mean, how do you know that he'll even understand you?
他不仅仅是一只猩猩
He's more than just an ape.
我带一些人到堡垒去
I'm gonna take some men up to Fort Point.
去看看我们的军火库里面还有没有什么是能用的
I'm gonna go through the armory. I'm gonna see what's still working.
你只有三天 如果你三天之内没有回来 我们就会去红木林
Three days. You're not back in three days we're going up there,
会杀死他们所有人
and we're gonna kill every last one of them.
卡佛去准备车子了
Carver is getting the trucks ready.
他和福斯特还有坎普马上就会过来
He'll be here with Foster and Kemp any minute.
你真的要带卡佛去? 他可是向他们开枪了
You're really taking Carver? I mean, he shot one of them.
我别无选择 他曾经在水利局工作过
I don't really have any choice. He used to work at the water department.
只有他知道那个大坝怎么工作的
He's the only one who knows how the dam works.
马尔科姆...
Malcolm...
你到底打算做什么? 你打算说什么?
what are you gonna do up there? What are you gonna say?
我会告诉他真相
I'll tell him the truth.
希望他心情正好
Hope I catch him in a good mood.
你觉得我疯了
You think I'm crazy.
我很担心
I'm worried.
嗯 我也是
Yeah, so am I.
我已经想过了...
I've gone over it in my head...
我觉得如果我连试都不试一下...
and I think if I don't at least try this...
我们一定会开战的
there's gonna be a war.
带上我吧 万一有人受伤的话 你需要我
Take me with you. What if someone gets hurt? You'll need me there.
我爱你
I love you.
但是我需要你留在这里
But I need you to stay here.
我也不希望亚历山大一个人留下
I don't want Alexander to be alone.
我也来
I'm coming, too.
孩子 这不安全
Son, it's not safe.
但是我和你们在一起会比留在这里更安全
But I'm safer with you than I am down here.
让我也去吧 求你了
I'm coming. Please.
大家不要离开车子
No one gets out of the trucks.
谁都不行
No one.
如果我两个小时之内没有回来 你带大家回城
If I'm not back in two hours, you get everyone back to the city.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
求你了 求你了 求你了
Please. Please. Please.
求你别杀了我
Please don't kill me.
先听我说
Just hear what I have to say.
我知道
I know.
你说过让我别再回来 我知道
"Don't come back." I know.
我本不会来的 可是...
I wouldn't be here unless it were...
行! 行! 行!
Okay! Okay! Okay!
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
我想给你看样东西 那地方离这里不远
I need to show you something. It's not far.
- 人类是骗子! - 不! 不是的!
- Human lies! - No! No!
我发誓 我没有
No, no, no. I swear.
我带你去看 你自然会明白的 求你了
If I could just show you, then you'll understand. Please.
带路吧
Show me.
我们之前叫这地方"小水坝"
This is what we used to call a "small hydro."
造它是为了供电给北部地区...
It was built to service areas to the north of here...
但我们正试着将电路重新接回城市里...
but we've been working to reroute the power lines to the city...
之前城市利用核能供电 但核燃料几年前燃烧殆尽
because the city used to run off nuclear power, but that ran out years ago.
我们现在只能靠柴油机和燃气机
So, we've been using diesel generators and gasifiers.
但如果我们能让这大坝重新运作...
But if we can just get this dam working...
就有可能解决一部分能源问题
then we have a shot at restoring limited power.
你听懂了吗?
Is any of this making any sense to you?
电... 灯
The... lights.
没错
Yes.
电灯
The lights.
这是你的家园 我保证 我对它没有任何恶意
This is your home and I don't want to take it away from you, I promise.
但如果你能同意我们解决...
But if you can let us do our work here...
你还带了其他人类?
You brought others?
就几个
Just a few.
我没有恶意 如果我有的话...
I'm not a threat. If I am...
那你就直接杀了我吧
then I guess you can kill me.
来啊!
Come on!
- 等等 等等! - 别开枪 别开枪
- Wait, wait, wait! - Stop, stop.
我们要把枪给他们
We need to give them our guns.
只有这么一个条件
That's the one condition.
- 这话什么意思? - 我们可以留下
- What does that mean? - We can stay.
如果人类有了电 他们会更危险!
If they get power, they'll be more dangerous!
为什么要帮他们!
Why help them!
人类看上去走投无路了...
They seem desperate...
如果我们不同意的话 人类估计会打上来
If we make them go, they'll attack.
那就让他们打
Let them.
趁人类势弱 我们一举消灭他们
We'll destroy them while they're weak.
那得死多少同胞?
And how many apes will die?
我们有和平相处的机会的...
We have one chance for peace...
让他们完成人类的工作 之后他们就会离开的
Let them do their human work. Then they'll go.
人类的工作?
Human work?
这是人类的杰作
Human work.
这也是人类的杰作
都是人类的杰作!
Human work!
科巴是说...
Koba say...
猩猩应该憎恨人类...
Apes should hate humans...
够了!
Enough!
从人类那里 科巴只学会了憎恨...
From humans Koba learned hate...
仅此而已
But nothing else.
嘿 你得吃点东西才行
Hey. You need to eat.
知道了
Okay.
今天你所做的一切 真是太勇敢了
That was brave, what you did today.
马尔科姆 我知道大家都指望你...
Malcolm. I know everyone's depending on you...
我不在乎这些 我不在乎
I don't care about that. I don't care about any of that.
我只关心那小子
I care about him.
他看到了小孩子不应该看到的事情 我不允许历史再重演了
He saw things that no kid should see, and I'm not letting us go back to that.
我知道
I know.
我一直试着想跟他更亲近点
I have been trying to get closer to him.
但是...
But...
你会的...
You will.
你知道它们的可怕之处吗?
You know the scary thing about them?
它们不需要能源 电灯
They don't need power, lights.
暖气 都不需要
Heat. Nothing.
- 嘿 伙计 - 这些都是他们的优势
- Hey, pal. - That's their advantage.
也是它们更强壮的原因
That's what makes them stronger.
马尔科姆 我觉得我们今晚应该有人放哨才行
Malcolm, I'm thinking one of us should stand guard tonight.
用什么放? 它们把枪都缴走了
With what? They took our guns.
如果它们要除掉我们 我们早就死了
If they wanted us dead, we would be dead already.
也许它们只是慢慢来而已 反正它们已经消灭半个地球的人类了
Maybe they're just taking their time. They killed off half the planet already.
拜托
Come on.
- 怎么了? - 你不会真的怪那些猩猩吧
- What? - You can't honestly blame the apes.
那我应该怪谁去? 本来就是猿类流感病毒
Who the hell else am I going to blame? It was the Simian Flu.
那也是科学家在实验室里研制出的病毒
It was a virus created by scientists in a lab.
那些大猩猩只是实验道具而已 它们也无可奈何
The chimps they were testing on didn't have a say in the matter.
别跟我说这些有的没的
Spare me the hippie-dippie bullshit.
你敢告诉我 你看到它们的时候 你没觉得恶心吗?
You're telling me you don't get sick to your stomach at the sight of them?
- 你之前不是有个女儿吗? - 卡佛 够了
- Didn't you have a little girl? - Carver, that's enough.
- 她怎么死的? - 够了!
- How did she die? - That's enough!
你老婆也是一样的
Or your wife, for that matter.
卡佛 你给我闭嘴 不然我就不客气了
Carver, you better shut up before I kick your ass.
好吧
Okay.
算我混蛋
I'm the asshole.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
你好像病了... 你还好吗?
You sound sick... You ok?
只是需要休息而已
Just need rest.
你担心那些人类...
You worry about the humans...
科巴在哪里?
Where's Koba?
还在生闷气
Still angry.
他说要出去打猎...
Said he was going hunting...
看 下面有人类!
Look, humans below!
我们干嘛来这里?
Why are we here?
凯撒相信人类...
Caesar trusts humans...
科巴不相信
Koba does not.
- 大部分武器都能正常使用 - 好的
- Most of the arsenal seems functional. - Good.
我们在后面测试确认
We're testing them out back.
嘿!
Hey!
不准动! 不准动 明白吗?
Don't you move! Don't move, do you understand me?
泰瑞! 泰瑞 快过来 快点!
Terry! Terry, get in here, quick!
卧槽
Holy shit.
我们怎么办? 怎么办?
What do we do? What do we do?
它从哪儿来的?
Where did he come from?
- 我们要开枪吗? - 也许吧 我也不知道
- Should we shoot him? - Maybe. I don't know.
你这样子长得真难看啊 是吧?
You are one ugly son of a bitch, aren't you?
哇哦 伙计
Whoa, man.
伙计 我猜它是饿了
Dude, I think he's hungry.
它肯定是跟它的部落走散了
He must have gotten separated from the others.
你迷路了? 想回家去吗?
You lost? Trying to get home?
快走! 滚出去 笨猴子!
Go on! Get out of here, stupid monkey!
- 快走 说你呢 快走! - 快走! 走!
- Go on. You heard him. Go! - Go! Go!
有足够的枪消灭每只猩猩...
Enough guns here to kill every ape...
必须警告凯撒
Must warn Caesar.
谁知道人类的真正目的是什么?
Who knows what humans are really doing up there?
我们必须打通这地方
We gotta clear this blockage.
我不知道你有个女儿
I didn't know you had a daughter.
是有个
Yeah.
她叫什么名字?
What was her name?
萨拉
Sarah.
节哀顺变
I'm really sorry.
现在我有你和你爸爸了 所以...
Well, now I have you and your dad, so...
也是
Yeah.
好的 你拉直了吗?
All right, you got that straight?
引线全部拉完了
That's all the wire we got.
准备爆破
Brace yourselves.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
- 老爸! - 马尔科姆!
- Dad! - Malcolm!
马尔科姆! 马尔科姆!
Malcolm! Malcolm!
老爸?
Dad?
卡佛不见了
I can't see Carver.
别!
Don't!
- 不要拔出来 - 明白
- Leave it there. - I got it.
骨头没断
It's not broken.
放手 好的
Let go. Good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你救了我们一命 我们有很多瓦砾要清理
You saved our lives. We've got a lot of debris to clear now.
- 我们估计还需要点时间 - 还要多久?
- We might need a bit more time. - How long?
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
嘿... 嘿...
Hey... hey...
你在干嘛? 包扎好了吗?
What are you doing? Are you finished?
你看什么看?
What are you looking at?
嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey!
嘿 走开!
Hey, get out of there!
- 嘿! 我毙了你! - 卡佛 你干什么?
- Hey! I'll kill you! - Carver, what're you doing?
不要! 不要! 凯撒 住手!
Don't! Don't! Caesar, no!
不要
No.
说过 不准有枪!
Said no guns!
- 不 别开枪 - 求你了
- No, don't. - Please.
我真的不知道
I didn't know.
人类马上离开!
Human leave now!
伙计 我们完蛋了
Man, we screwed now.
马尔科姆?
Malcolm?
马尔科姆 你去哪里? 马尔科姆
Malcolm, where are you going? Malcolm.
求你了 求你了 我只是想跟他说几句
Please, please, I just need to speak to him.
对不起 这全是我的错 我马上让他离开这里
I'm sorry. That was all my fault. But I will make him leave.
这是我的家
This my home.
- 你不应该在这里 - 我知道
- You should not be here. - I understand.
马尔科姆
Malcolm.
她病了
She's sick.
她这样子多久了?
How long has she been this way?
我有药
I have medicine.
抗生素
Antibiotics.
也许她能帮忙
Maybe she can help.
不相信你
Do not trust you.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
但相信我... 我们并不是都跟他一样的
But believe me... we are not all like him.
求你了
Please.
让我们帮帮你
Let us help you.
就一天
One day.
你们再多待一天
You stay one day.
- 我们估计要更多时间 - 只准一天!
- We might need more time. - One day!
猩猩会帮忙
Ape will help.
我才不帮忙!
I will not help!
- 这欺人太甚了 伙计! - 赶他走
- This is bullshit, man! - Get him out of here.
快走! 够了 快点 离开这里
Move! That's enough. Come on, get out of here.
快点 伙计
Come on, man.
可以了吗?
Okay?
快走 快点!
Move, come on!
给我进去!
Get in!
明天见 混球
See you tomorrow, asshole.
我刚刚从城市回来 人类很危险!
Just came from the city. Humans very dangerous!
凯撒在哪里?
Where is Caesar?
和人类在一起...
With the humans...
哎 亚历克斯 这接口坏了 再找个过来
Yo, Alex. This relay's busted. See if there's another one.
好的
Yeah.
凯撒
Caesar.
嘿!
Hey!
不! 别这样 不要! 不!
No! No, no, no, don't! No! No! No!
凯撒在哪里? 我要见凯撒
Where Caesar? Want Caesar.
凯撒!
Caesar!
人类攻击你的子女
Humans attack your sons.
而你却让他们留下来!
You let them stay!
置同胞于危难!
Put apes in danger!
比起猩猩 凯撒更加喜欢...
Caesar love humans more...
人类!
than apes!
甚至高于你的...
More than your...
子孙
sons.
猩猩...
Ape...
不会...
not...
自相残杀...
kill... ape.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
你是我的儿子...
You are my son...
我需要你服从...
I need you to listen...
你不准备告诉凯撒我们发现枪械的事情?
You didn't tell Caesar about the guns we found?
你也不准多嘴
Neither will you.
你父亲不再相信我了
Your father doesn't trust me now.
你需要多保护他
You need to protect him.
他对人类的爱...
His love for humans...
让他迷失了判断
makes him blind.
我知道...
I know...
人类多待一刻...
As long as they are here...
我就越担忧凯撒的性命
I fear for Caesar's life.
谢谢你昨天救我
For yesterday.
看 看
Look. Look.
观看 观看
Watch. Watch.
"今天是周五
"It was Friday.
下午天气真好
A real nice afternoon.
很暖和
Warm.
我们在泳池...
We were hanging...
我们在泳池旁边的...
We were hanging out...
啤酒桶那边消遣"
at this kegger down at the swimming hole."
消遣
Hanging out.
挂在那边
Hanging.
这边 你认字吗?
Here. You can read?
这可是个好东西
Now, this is the good stuff.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
你这是个什么情况? 我们不是让你回家了吗?
What the hell is wrong with you? I thought we told you to go home!
不准过来!
No!
不准! 快走!
No! Go!
- 这个他到懂 是吧? - 没错
- He understood that, didn't he? - Yeah.
悠着点 悠着点!
Hey, hey, hey!
悠着点
Hey, hey.
嘿
Hey.
- 哇哦 哇哦 我啊 - 嘿 嘿
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. - Hey, hey, hey.
- 我觉得他喜欢你 - 闭嘴
- I think he likes you. - Shut up.
没事 没事
All right, all right.
你也想喝一杯 丑东西?
You want a drink, fugly?
快点 给他来点
Go on, give him some.
给他点 伙计 看看会发生什么
Give him some, man. See what happens.
给你 哇哦 嘿!
There you go. Whoa, hey!
哇哦 哇哦 哇哦!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
见鬼!
Shit!
- 好东西 是吧? - 是吧 是吧
- That's good, huh? - Yeah, yeah.
嘿 嘿 嘿! 够了 悠着点
Hey, hey, hey! Okay. All right.
- 当心 - 好的
- Easy. - Yeah.
- 当心 - 当心
- Easy. - Easy.
好了...
All right...
马尔科姆! 马尔科姆!
Malcolm! Malcolm!
怎么了? 出什么事了?
What is it? What happened?
通电了
It worked.
至少这边通了 等到城市就知道那边的情况了
At least here it did. We'll know when we get back to the city.
信任
Trust.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
你们这群混蛋!
You son of a bitch!
快看... 电灯
The... lights.
感觉好点了吗?
Feeling better?
母亲?
Mother?
人类的枪!
Human gun!
快跑
Run.
人类杀了凯撒!
Humans kill Caesar!
烧毁猩猩的家园!
Burn ape home!
快点! 抓住他们!
Go! Get them!
猩猩必须攻击人类的城市!
Apes must attack human city!
反击!
Fight back!
来吧 为凯撒而战!
Come, fight for Caesar!
母猿和孩子留在树林...
Females and young stay in woods...
我们去城里!
We go to the city!
我们会为你父亲报仇的!
We will avenge your father's death!
艾莉! 艾莉
Ellie! Ellie.
旧金山寻求通信 如果有人收到这条信息...
This is San Francisco attempting contact. If anyone is receiving this message...
我们需要确认你的身份和位置 完毕
we ask that you identify yourself and your location. Over.
行动 行动!
Move, move!
如果你收到这个信号 请回复你的位置 完毕
If you are receiving this signal, please state your location. Over.
重复 旧金山请求建立通信
Repeat. This is San Francisco attempting to establish contact.
如果你收到这个信号
If you are receiving this signal
请回复你的身份和位置 完毕
please state your identity and your location. Over.
- 什么事? - 猩猩攻击了军械库 长官
- What is it? - The apes attacked the armory, sir.
警报! 警报!
Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm!
把他们挡在城墙外! 把他们挡在城墙外!
Keep them off the walls! Keep them off the walls!
快走! 迅速就位
Let's go! Get into position.
- 准备好了吗? - 好了 长官
- You ready? - Yes, sir.
好
Good.
听我说
Listen to me.
我们是幸存者!
We are survivors!
现在他们手里可能有我们的枪...
Now, they may have got their hands on some of our guns...
但这不会让他们变成人
but that does not make them men.
他们是动物! 我们要赶他们回去!
They are animals! We will push them back!
把他们赶下去!
Drive them down!
他们就不会走进这些门!
And they will not get through these doors!
在这里! 加利福尼亚街!
There! California Street!
把火箭发射器给我!
Bring me the rocket launcher!
我们有信标显示我们的位置 我们需要帮助 我们受到了攻击
We have a beacon marking our location. Please, we need help. We are under attack.
旧金山 请重复
San Francisco. Repeat.
- 喂? - 听到了吗?
- Hello? - Do you copy?
人类在逃跑! 抓住他们!
Humans escaping! Capture them!
我们肯定越来越近了
We must be getting close.
我好像看见了 就在这里!
I think I see it. It's down here!
爸爸!
Dad!
天啊 马尔科姆!
Oh, my God. Malcolm!
艾莉 帮我
Ellie, help me.
我的...
My...
儿子...
son...
我的...
My...
家人...
family...
在哪里?
Where?
我不知道
I don't know.
尽量不要说话 你需要休息
Try not to speak. You need to rest.
按着
Hold.
- 他已经流了很多血 - 他能挺过来吗?
- He's lost a lot of blood. - Is he going to make it?
我不明白
I don't understand.
卡佛在哪里拿到的枪?
Where did Carver get the gun?
- 他为什么这么做? - 猩猩...
- Why would he do this? - Ape...
什么?
What?
猩猩...
Ape...
对我...
did...
开的枪
this.
上车
Get in the truck.
跟着人类到这里 他们藏在各个地方!
Followed the humans here. Hiding everywhere!
我们一定把他们全都抓起来!
We must catch them all!
- 杀了他 - 不要 不要
- Kill him. - No, no, no.
动手 灰烬...
Go ahead Ash...
让人类付出代价
make humans pay.
凯撒不会想要这样的
Caesar wouldn't want this.
凯撒死了...
Caesar gone...
现在猩猩们...
Apes follow...
跟随科巴
Koba now.
- 天啊 看 聚居地着火了 - 我们要去哪里?
- Oh, my God. Look, the colony's on fire. - Where are we going to go?
凯撒 什么?
Caesar, what?
- 是这里吗? 我们快到了吗? - 他要带我们去哪?
- Is this it? Are we close? - Where is he taking us?
马尔科姆 停车!
Malcolm, stop!
我不明白 我们来这里做什么?
I don't understand. What are we doing here?
这不重要 我们只需要一个给他藏身的地方
It doesn't matter. We just need a place to hide him
直到我们弄明白家园发生了什么
until we find out what's going on at home.
把桌子推开
Go move the table.
好了 放这里
Okay. Right here.
好
Okay.
爸爸 看
Dad, look.
看啊
Look.
我们需要做手术 我什么工具都没有
We need to operate. I don't have anything.
手术器械包还在原来那里 但是那里...
There's a surgical kit back at the place, but that's...
我去拿
I'll go.
- 这不安全 - 他是唯一能阻止这场战争的人
- It's not safe. - He's the only one that can stop this.
人类!
Humans!
你们现在是猩猩的囚犯了!
You ape prisoner now!
你们会尝到生活在笼子里的滋味
You will know life in cage.
还有更多的人在外面
More humans out there.
去! 找到他们!
Go! Find them!
毛里斯...?
Maurice...?
科巴说...
Koba said...
我们对你爸爸太忠诚了
we're too loyal to your father.
保护好自己
Protect yourself.
该死!
Shit!
嘿 等等
Hey, wait.
你爸爸
Your father.
他还活着
He's alive.
我拿到了
I got it.
他怎么样了?
How is he?
你的... 妈妈
Your... mother.
弟弟
Brother.
安全吗?
Safe?
暂时安全
For now.
不
No.
不是人类
Not human.
是科巴
Koba.
马尔科姆
Malcolm.
好
Yeah.
凯撒
Caesar.
我们现在要做手术
We need to do this now.
儿子
Son.
他怎么样了?
How is he?
还不知道
We'll see.
他很强壮
He's very strong.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
对不起...
I'm so sorry...
为所有的一切道歉
For everything.
不
No.
我...
I...
是我的错
am to blame.
但科巴背叛了你
But Koba betrayed you.
我...
I...
选择了相信他...
chose to trust him...
因为他是猩猩
because he is ape.
我总是以为...
I always think...
猩猩比人类好
ape better than human.
我现在知道了...
I see now...
我们和人类有多像
how much like them we are.
科巴现在在哪?
Where Koba now?
在人类的塔上...
On the human tower...
还有忠诚于他的猩猩
Loyal apes around him.
那些不追随他的呢?
And those who not follow?
成了阶下囚
Prisoners.
毛里斯
Maurice.
火箭
Rocket.
科巴杀了灰烬
Koba killed Ash.
其他猩猩出于害怕而追随他
Fear makes others follow.
但是等他们看见你活着...
But when they see you alive...
他们会从科巴那儿回到你身边
They will turn from Koba.
如果我身体很弱 就不会了
Not if I am weak.
猩猩总是追随最强的人
Ape always seek strongest branch.
我一定要阻止他
I must do something to stop him.
爸爸
Father.
让我帮你
Let me help you.
求你了 让我们离开这里吧!
Please, let us out of here!
好
Okay.
凯撒 看
Caesar, look.
苹果 苹果
Apple. Apple.
很好
Good.
家 家
Home. Home.
家园
Home.
没错
Yes.
这是你的家 你的家
This is your home. Your home.
好 好
Good. Good.
做得好
That's good.
抱歉 我不是有意打扰你
Sorry. I didn't mean to intrude.
已经两天了
It's been two days.
你儿子还没回来吗?
Your son is not back yet?
那是谁?
Who was that?
录像里的
On the video.
一个好人
A good man.
像你一样
Like you.
他们需要在不被看见的情况下进入塔内
They need to get to the tower without being seen.
我会带他走地下通道
I'm gonna take him through the subway.
我爱你
I love you.
科巴派手下去接母猿和孩子了
Koba sent for the females and young.
他们已经在路上
They're on their way.
妈妈也是
Mother too.
得走了 马上!
Must go. Now!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
谁在哪儿? 如果你是人类 你最好应一声!
Who's there? If you're human, you better say so!
是我! 马尔科姆! 别开枪!
It's me! It's Malcolm! Don't shoot!
梯子... 爬梯子
Stairs... take the stairs.
你会上到街附近 好吗? 走
They'll bring you around and up under the street, okay? Go.
谢谢
Thank you.
相信我
Trust.
好了 我就过去!
All right, I'm coming out!
别开枪!
Don't shoot!
嘿! 看看我找到谁了
Hey! Look who I found.
我不知道你逃出来了
I didn't know if you'd made it out.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
别担心 我们会扭转局势的
Don't worry. We're gonna turn all this around.
- 什么意思? 出什么事了? - 猩猩 他们占领了整座塔
- What do you mean? What's going on? - The apes. They're all over the tower.
- 我失去信号了 联系不上了 - 继续尝试
- I lost the signal. It dropped out. - Keep trying.
马尔科姆 看这个
Malcolm, look at this.
五磅的C-4炸弹
C-4. Five-pound blocks.
我们刚刚安装好
We just started setting them.
它们会炸掉整座塔
They're gonna take down the whole tower.
一次性把他们全炸掉
Blast them all at once.
你可以帮我们
We could use your help.
旧金山请求通信 如果有人收到信息...
This is San Francisco attempting contact. If anyone is receiving this...
我们需要你的身份和位置 完毕
we ask that you identify yourself and your location. Over.
来 给你
Here. Come on.
如果有人收到信息 我们需要你的身份...
If anyone is receiving this, we ask that you identify yourself...
和位置 完毕
and your location. Over.
旧金山请求通信
This is San Francisco attempting contact.
如果有人收到信息 我们需要你的身份
If anyone is receiving this we ask that you identify yourself
和位置
and your location.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
如果有人收到信息 我们需要你的身份...
If anyone is receiving this, we ask that you identify yourself...
和位置 完毕
and your location. Over.
德雷福斯
Dreyfus.
- 有人听到我说话吗? - 维纳
- Can anybody hear me? - Werner.
对不起 我不能让你这么做
I'm sorry, but I can't let you do this.
我们要给他一个机会
We need to give him a chance.
我们需要给他点时间 他正在上面
We need to give him some time. He's up there right now.
谁在上面?
Who's up there?
凯撒在这里没有地位
Caesar has no place here.
猩猩现在...
Apes follow...
追随科巴
Koba now.
追随科巴...
Follow Koba...
打仗
to war.
猩猩赢了战争!
Apes win war!
猩猩团结的力量大!
Apes together strong!
凯撒r...
Caesar...
弱爆了
weak.
科巴更弱
Koba weaker.
你这是疯了吗?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
不 我看到他们的生存方式
No, I've seen things. I've seen the way they are.
他们想要的和我们一样 生存 他们不想要战争
They want what we want, to survive. They don't want a war.
他们是动物! 他们攻击了我们!
They're animals! They attacked us!
因为他们以为是我们先攻击的 他们以为他死了 可他没死...
Because they thought we attacked them. They think that he's dead, but he's not...
坐下 芬尼! 坐下!
Sit down, Finney! Sit down!
像兄弟一样相信科巴
Trusted Koba like brother.
凯撒和人类才是兄弟!
Caesar brother to human!
科巴是为猩猩而战!
Koba fight for ape!
解放猩猩!
Free ape!
杀猩猩
Kill ape.
科巴为他自己而战
Koba fight for Koba.
科巴...
Koba...
来自于笼子
belong in cage.
我知道这听起来多荒唐
I know how this must sound.
我觉得你没有...
I don't think you have any...
你觉得阻止我有用吗? 他们就要来了
Do you think stopping me will matter? They're coming.
现在 我们已经和北方的军事基地取得联系
Now, we made contact with a military base up north.
他们已经在路上了!
They're already on their way!
是真的
It's true.
德雷福斯! 你在做什么 兄弟?
Dreyfus! What are you doing, man?
我在拯救人类
I'm saving the human race.
不!
No!
猩猩...
Ape...
不会杀...
not kill...
同类
ape.
你...
You are...
不是猩猩
not ape.
不!
No!
放开他!
Leave him!
你们在这里不安全
You're not safe here.
他们和外界取得了联系 其他人正在来的路上 士兵们
They made contact. Other people are coming. Soldiers.
你现在必须离开 都要离开
You have to leave now. Everyone.
如果你不走 这里又将是一场大战
If you don't go, it'll be all-out war.
战争...
War...
已经...
has already...
开始了
begun.
猩猩开始了战争
Ape started war.
而人类...
And human...
人类不会原谅的
Human will not forgive.
你必须走...
You must go...
在开战前离开
before fighting begins.
对不起...
I am sorry...
我的朋友
my friend.
我以为我们还有机会
I thought we had a chance.
我也曾经这么想
I did, too.